LUKMAN AYODEJI ADEBOYE

+44(0)7770709882 lukman.adeboye@outlook.com

17, Mitchell Road, Wharley End, Cranfield, Bedford, Bedfordshire. United Kingdom

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A dependable and well-practised Engineer in the Industrial and manufacturing engineering landscape both in heavy-duty industrial processing units and across renowned Original Equipment Manufacturers (OEMs) for power, utility and cement manufacturing industries. Professional experience in the areas of operations and strategy, after-sales support, project execution, equipment commissioning, and plant enhancement or retrofitting activities. My diverse competencies, mostly in multicultural environments, is informed by deep industry knowledge and experience across markets and locations and will bring a depth of senior leadership interactions to support strategic corporate goals.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Led the technical department of Loesche GmbH's UAE subsidiary in Dubai in sustaining equipment spare-parts sales, winning around 10% new customers and regaining about 25% customers lost to competitors
- Spearheaded the execution of on-site experimental solutions to complex drive train resonance problem of vertical grinding mills, involving the application of specialised equipment and coordination with the R & D department
- Performed around 10 successful hot-commissioning leading to new equipment (dry-grinding vertical roller mills for coal, cement raw material and clinker) handover to customers upon completion of performance guarantee tests
- Delivered collaboratively plant enhancement or retrofitting programmes to customers with obsolete units, enhancing their throughput by 15%, while maintaining product quality, and saving on specific power consumption in the Middle East and Sub-Sahara Africa
- Conducted frequent customer outreach programmes such as technical audits, personnel training, troubleshooting, and participated in negotiation of major upgradation projects
- Volunteered as an energy and water representative in Cranfield University Green Team committee.

EDUCATION

MSc in Advanced Mechanical Engineering, Cranfield University, Cranfield, UK October 2023 - September 2024

- Modules: Assessing risk and failure, Engineering project management, Fluid mechanics and loading, Computational fluid dynamics for renewable energy, Engineering stress analysis, Structural integrity.
- Group Project: Experimental tests of floating breakwater with configurable bio-inspired fin adjustment
- Thesis: Design of floating charging Solar charging infrastructure for the Port of Dover

MSc in Energy Technology and Management, University of Ibadan, Nigeria

May 2011 - May 2014

- Modules: Energy transmission & distribution, Energy management & planning, Conventional energy conversion, Tero-technology, New and Renewable energy conversion, Energy modelling & forecasting, Energy policy & economics, Energy resources, Energy ecology & environment, Tropical energy & environmental issues, Seminars.
- Thesis: Thermo-economic and environmental analyses of dry process cement manufacturing in Nigeria

BSc, University of Lagos, Lagos, Nigeria

May 2003 - January 2008

Modules: Radiation & mass transfer, Energy sources & utilisation, production engineering, vibration technology & control, Engineering plasticity, Thermal engines, Mechanical engineering design, Applied thermodynamics, Operation research, and Automatic control.

CAREER HISTORY

Loesche GmbH (UAE Subsidiary) - Commissioning Engineer, Dubai, UAE Subsidiary - Service Engineer

August 2021 - August 2023

An innovative engineering company specialised in equipment manufacturing for mineral, ore, power and utility industries.

- Complied with relevant, statutory safety, health and environmental standards
- Represented and promoted the interest of Loesche group during meetings with customer, partners & subcontractors
- · Consulted various customers for operational stability, improvement and enhancement projects
- Performed complex field tests on selected plant sites
- Supervised technical repairs, modifications and upgrades for the Loesche dry grinding vertical mills Ensured technical guarantees were met and collaborated on drawing up thermal balances and process engineering flow sheets Provided technical training and mentoring for colleagues and customers' operative staff

Loesche Nigeria Engineer - Commissioning Process Engineer

August 2017 - January 2021

An innovative engineering company specialised in equipment manufacturing for mineral, ore, power and utility industries.

- · Trained on equipment commissioning, customer engagement, and stakeholder management
- Conducted various on-site troubleshooting, training, as well as audits and plant optimisation
- · Carried out commissioning of newly erected mills, and supervised performance guarantee tests
- Conducted market surveys and data collection for onward analyses
- Implemented project-specific coordination on respective construction sites

Lafarge Africa Plc, Mfamosing II Plant, Nigeria, Production Engineer

July 2016 - July 2017

A pioneer cement manufacturing company in Nigeria, renowned for its in-dept know-how and quality product offerings

- Monitored cement production operation against defined operation parameters
- Ensured equipment work reliably according to their specification
- Investigated operational upsets, problems and diagnosed faults
- Managed multi-discipline production shift team to deliver on production volumes and quality targets Collaborated in scheduled maintenance planning and execution Conducted appraisals for direct reports, and contributed to their continuous development programmes

FLSmidth (Jersey), Sumbe, Angola, Central Control Room Operator

June 2015 - April 2016

A leading Original Equipment Manufacturer in the mineral, ore and utility industries head-quartered in Denmark

- · Operated pyro-process, dry-grinding mill, and auxiliary equipment remotely from central control room
- Investigated operational upsets, problems and diagnosed faults
- Collaborated in scheduled maintenance planning and execution

Lafarge Africa Plc and NLSupervision Ltd, Nigeria, Central Control Room Operator

January 2010 - May 2015

A pioneer cement manufacturing company in Nigeria, renowned for its in depth know-how and quality product offerings

- Developed collaboration, leadership, problem-solving skills
- Enhanced my resilience, decision making, influencing and personal organisation skills
- Gained key technical competencies such as remote process equipment operation, problem-solving, and continuing professional development

SKILLS, INTERESTS & EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Languages: Fluent English
- IT Skills: Confident IT user. Experienced with MS Suite. Knowledge of MATLAB/Simulink
- Individual Interests: Mentoring, leadership, travelling (travelled across Pan-Africa and the Middle East)
- Extra-curricular Activity: Course representative Advanced Mechanical Engineering 2023/24; Cranfield University Student Ambassador, 2023/24 session
- **Memberships**: Mechanical engineer Council for the regulation of engineering in Nigeria (COREN), Project management professional (PMP), Student Member Energy Institute, Student Member Institute of Marine Engineering, Science and Technology (IMarEST)
- Professional/Technical training: Professional sales training with ILM certification, Six Sigma Black & Green Belts (CSSBB)